Planned Parenthood of Southern Arizona Collection, 1938-1987
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
The Planned Parenthood of Southern Arizona Collection, 1938-1987
MS 371
Planned Parenthood of Southern Arizona
The Planned Parenthood of Southern Arizona collection contains newspaper clippings, printed ephemera, and photographs, including materials by and about Margaret Sanger.
1 linear feet (2 boxes)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
A small Tucson birth control clinic, known as Clinica para Madres or Mother's Clinic, located at 28 E. Corral Street opened in December 1934. Margaret Sanger, pioneer of the birth control movement, offered her support in the establishment of the clinic and its purpose to provide birth control information, products and services for woman. The Tucson birth control clinic changed names and location thru the decades - Planned Parenthood of Tucson, Inc., 1950s to Planned Parenthood Center of Tucson, 1970s and finally to Planned Parenthood of Southern Arizona, serving two locations. This collection contains newspaper clippings, printed ephemera and photographs from the scrapbooks of Planned Parenthood of Tucson, which documents some of the history and people of the organization plus local and world events from 1938 to 1987.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series.
Series I: Scrapbooks, 1955-1987
Series II: Margaret Sanger Materials, 1938-1961
Scope and Content Note
This collection is organized into two series, Series I: Scrapbooks. Series II: Margaret Sanger Materials, contains chiefly correspondence with Christine A. Bloom concerning the establishment of the clinic in Tucson; and miscellaneous materials by or about Margaret Sanger.
Access Terms
Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966 -- Correspondence.
Gardner, B. Delworth, 1928-
Murphy, Lew.
Green, Ruth.
Wattleton, Faye.
Bloom, Christine A.
Birth control clinics -- Arizona -- Tucson -- History.
Birth control clinics -- Arizona -- Douglas -- History.
Container List
- Series 1: Scrapbooks, 1955-1987
  - Scrapbook #1, 1955-1966
    - Newspaper Clippings,1955 - 1960. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Photographs and Program, 1955 - 1966. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook #2, 1959-1979
    - Newspaper Clippings,1959 - 1966. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1967 - 1977. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlets and Reports, 1966 - 1979. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Photograph, ca. 1970. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook #3, 1962-1965
    - Newspaper Clippings,1962 - 1963. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1964. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Pamphlets and Reports, 1965. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook #4, 1964-1969
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1966. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1967. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1967. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1968 - 1969. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Printed Ephemera. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook #5, 1965-1987
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1965 - 1966. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook #6, 1959-1979
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1965 - 1971. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook #7, 1976-1980
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1976 - 1980. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Photographs and Printed Ephemera, 1977 - 1978. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Photographs and Printed Ephemera, 1978 - 1979. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Photograph, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Photographs and Printed Ephemera, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook #8, 1981-1982
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1981 - 1982. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Photographs and Printed Ephemera, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook #9, 1982-1985
    - Photographs, ca. 1981 - 1983. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, ca. 1982 - 1985. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series 2: Margaret Sanger Materials, 1938 to 1961
  - Correspondence and photographs, ca. 1938 - 1961. (Box 2, Folder 11)